<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thibaut Jombart website</title>
    <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thibaut Jombart website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 14:15:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher in outbreak response analytics, with a background in biostatistics, population genetics, and R programming. My research focusses on developing new methodologies and tools for understanding how infectious diseases spread, and how we can control them.
I wear several hats, including:
 Associate Professor in Outbreak Analytics at the London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine Senior Lecturer in Genetic Analysis at Imperial College London A member of the UK Public Health Rapid Support Team Founder and current President of the R Epidemics Consortium (RECON), an NGO for the development of free data analytics resources for health emergencies Extreme metal vocalist (currently innactive).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/group/</guid>
      <description>Current members  Amy Dighe (PhD student, ICL, 2017-) Dr Tim Taylor (Research Fellow LSHTM, 2020-) Anne Suffel (MSc student, LSHTM, 2020-) Emily Meyer (MSc student, LSHTM, 2020-) Allegra Wilson (MSc student, LSHTM, 2020-) Srikant Mohan (MSc student, LSHTM, 2020-)  Alumni  Finlay Campbell (MRes student 2016, PhD student 2016-2019, Research Associate 2019-2020) Zhian Kamvar (Research Associate, 2018-2020) Janetta Skarp (MRes student, 2018-2019) Amrish Baidjoe (postdoc, 2018-2019) Martin Hinsch (postdoc, 2017-2018) Tim McMackin (MPH student, 2015-2016) Anil Keshwani (MSc student, co-supervision with Tini Garske, 2015-2016) Lucy Tran (MSc student, co-supervision with Nick Croucher, 2015-2016) Joel Hellewell (Wellcome Trust funded MRes, 2014-2015) Camilla Strang (MSc student 2014-2015) Caitlin Collins (Research Assistant, 2013-2014) Yee Loong Low (Master student, 2014) Veronika Valovicova (Master student, 2013) Oluyemisi Khalidson (Master student, 2014)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>RECON learn Most of the training material I currently develop is hosted on the RECON learn platform. This includes lectures, praticals, and code gists.
Lectures  Introduction to phylogenetics Reproducibility using R Primer on statistical analysis of outbreaks Outbreak reconstruction using outbreaker2  Practicals  Phylogenetics using R Simulated Ebola response 1 Simulated Ebola response 2  Podcasts I have started experimenting with podcast in 2018. Most podcasts are under the RECON R tips umbrella, but I also occasionally post other videos, typically population genetics / statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Statistics These were last updated on the 29-08-2019.
Web of science:
 citations: 9,243 h-index: 30  Google scholar:
 citations: 12,477 h-index: 35 h10-index: 56  List of publications This list was last updated on the 29-08-2019.
  Jit M, Jombart T, Nightingale ES, et al. 2020. Estimating number of cases and spread of coronavirus disease (COVID-19) using critical care admissions, United Kingdom, February to March 2020. Euro Surveill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email This is the best way to contact me: thibautjombart@gmail.com.
Address *From 1st September 2018:*Department of Infectious Disease EpidemiologyLondon School of Hygiene and Tropical MedicineKeppel StreetLondon WC1E 7HTUnited Kingdom
*Until 1st September 2018:*Department of Infectious Disease EpidemiologySchool of Public Health, Imperial College LondonSt Mary’s Campus, Norfolk PlaceLondon W2 1PGUnited KingdomPhone 0044 (0)20 7594 3658
Appointment To book an appointment, please use calendly - it is fast and simple, and more reliable than emails!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why go open?</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/open_publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 14:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/open_publishing/</guid>
      <description>I think the first time I ranted publicly about publishing was during Epidemics6. At the time, I was making a plea for open software practices in science, which most people seem now to agree on: transparent, free, reproducible science seems to be the way forward. Practicing my talk for this conference organised by a large publishing company, I realised these ideals were thrown away in one of the most important aspects in a researcher’s life, the publication of peer reviewed papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola outbreak: what can we say with limited data?</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/ebola_simulations_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 14:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/ebola_simulations_2018/</guid>
      <description>Context Disclaimer: this blog post only represents my views, and not that of my institution or my collaborators.
On the 8th May 2018, the Ministry of Health of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) has notified the WHO of two confirmed cases of Ebola virus disease (EVD) reported in the Bikoro health zone, Equateur province. While the WHO and the international community seems to have reacted very quickly to the situation, data in the early stages of an outbreak are always scarce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>