<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thibaut Jombart website</title>
    <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Thibaut Jombart website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a researcher in outbreak response analytics, with a background in biostatistics, population genetics, and R programming. I currently work as a lecturer in the Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology at Imperial College London. My research focusses on developing new methodologies and tools for understanding how infectious diseases spread, and how we can control them.
You can find my CV here, and my PhD thesis (in French) there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/group/</guid>
      <description>Amrish Baidjoe  Amrish joined in September 2017. He is a field epidemiologist and microbiologist who worked for years on Malaria and Salmonella epidemiology, with some substantial experience in virology. A former EPIET fellow, Amrish is the current president of the EPIET Alumni network. He works on outbreak response and humanitarian crises, develops training material for outbreak analysis, and runs workshops.  Finlay Campbell  Finlay joined in February 2016 as a Master student, and started his PhD in September 2016, in a co-supervision with Neil Ferguson and Anne Cori.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/resources/</guid>
      <description>RECON learn Most of the training material I currently develop is hosted on the RECON learn platform. This includes lectures, praticals, and code gists.
Lectures  Introduction to phylogenetics Reproducibility using R Primer on statistical analysis of outbreaks Outbreak reconstruction using outbreaker2  Practicals  Phylogenetics using R Simulated Ebola response 1 Simulated Ebola response 2  
Podcasts I have started experimenting with podcast in 2018. Most podcasts are under the RECON R tips umbrella, but I also occasionally post other videos, typically population genetics / statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>As of November 2017, I have decided to promote open, transparent publishing, i.e. publishing in which:
 papers are freely available to the community reviews are fully published referees are explicitly named  I no longer review for, edit for, or submit to journals which do no fulfil these criteria.
Statistics These were last updated on the 22-12-2017.
web of science:
 citations: 6,381 h-index: 26  Google scholar:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email This is the best way to contact me: thibautjombart@gmail.com.
Address MRC Centre for Outbreak Analysis and Modelling
Department of Infectious Disease Epidemiology
Imperial College London
St Mary’s Campus, Norfolk Place
London W2 1PG
United Kingdom
Phone 0044 (0)20 7594 3658</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ebola outbreak: what can we say with limited data?</title>
      <link>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/ebola_simulations_2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thibautjombart.netlify.com/post/ebola_simulations_2018/</guid>
      <description>Context Disclaimer: this blog post only represents my views, and not that of my institution or my collaborators.
On the 8th May 2018, the Ministry of Health of the Democratic Republic of the Congo (DRC) has notified the WHO of two confirmed cases of Ebola virus disease (EVD) reported in the Bikoro health zone, Equateur province. While the WHO and the international community seems to have reacted very quickly to the situation, data in the early stages of an outbreak are always scarce.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>